Barzillai Pease Journals
Barzillai Pease Journals
- [Volume 9], 1826
  - Journal 19 (26 p.): Schooner Margaret, Darius D. Dennis, Mister, to Bermuda and Guadalupe, June 3, 1826-Sep 9, 1826; daily entries (Box 1)
    Pease comments on the very poor crew of the Margaret. After arriving at Bermuda on June 22, the ship caught fire in the harbor and sank. The captain was robbed so he could not pay Pease his wages. He describes the island of Bermuda before leaving it to sail 16 days to St. Martin's in Anguilla. In Bermuda Pease had been offered $5000 for a sworn statement of the location of treasure he apparently was seeking: he says he would accept $10,000. He offered the captain $5000 to $10,000 to take him to St. Martin's. When Pease found no treasure, the captain was very angry so that Pease records that he wishes he were off the ship. At Dominique he found a ship bound for Providence and took passage, arriving in New York Sept. 9, 1826.